Finding Aid for the Edwin S. Shneidman Papers LSC.0385
UCLA Library Special Collections
- ESS Publications, Series 3.
  - Assorted ESS published & unpublished articles., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 19)
    Includes Can a Young Person Write His Own Obituary, proposal abstract for The Self-Destructive Mind, draft of The Death of Ahab, Death and the College Student
  - ESS papers., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 20)
    Includes drafts of the following articles: A Socio-Psychological Investigation of Suicide, Postvention: The Care of the Bereaved, A Set of Proposals for the Suicide Prevention Center, Inc.,
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 21)
    Includes drafts of the following articles: First Aid in Suicidal Crisis, Some Recent Developments in Suicidology, Suicide Notes Reconsidered
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 22)
    Includes draft of Suicide and Success, Logical Content Analysis, Psycho- Logic: A Personality Approach to Patterns of Thinking, draft of Some Aspects of Psychotherapy with Dying Persons
  - Shneidman publications., 1960s. (Box 21, Folder 23)
    Includes drafts of Sleep and Self-Destruction: A Phenomenological Approach and Psycho-Logic: An Explication of Argument,
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1970s - 1990s. (Box 21, Folder 24)
    Includes A Psychological Approach to Suicide, At the Point of No Return, Suicide (in the Encyclopedia Britannica), Suicide Notes Reconsidered, Perturbation and Lethality as Precursors of Suicide in a Gifted Group
  - Various ESS & others' writings., 1970s & 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 25)
    Includes hand and typewritten notes, The Living of Charlotte Perkins Gilman by Charlotte Perkins Gilman, The Journal of Andrew Bihaly by Anthony Tuttle, The Turning Point by Klaus Mann, and draft of Cesare Pavese: Italian Poet and Novelist
  - ESS writings., 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 26)
    Includes draft of Death Documents, work copy of The Definition of Suicide, draft of Avoiding Suicide, handwritten notes
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1980s - 1990s. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Includes draft of A Psychological Approach to Suicide, Preventing Suicide, Aphorisms of Suicide and Some Implications for Psychotherapy, A Multidimensional View of Suicide,
  - ESS Suicide Articles., 1950s. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Includes TAT Heroes of Suicidal and Non-Suicidal Subjects and Suicide and the Police Officer
  - ESS Suicide Articles., 1960s. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Includes The Psychography of Suicide, Suicide, Sleep, and Death, How to Prevent Suicide pamphlets,
  - ESS Suicide Articles., 1970s. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Includes Prevention of Suicide: A Challenge for Community Science, Can a Young Person Write His Own Obituary, and Perturbation and Lethality as precursors of Suicide in a Gifted Group,
  - ESS Suicide Articles., 1980s. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Includes Aphorisms of Suicide and Some Implications for Psychotherapy, The Logical Environment of Suicide,
  - ESS Suicide Articles., 1990s. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Includes Further Reflection on Suicide and Psychache, Suicide and the Britannica, Some Controversies in Suicidology: Toward a Mentalistic Discipline
  - Death & Suicide Articles., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Includes Suicide Notes Reconsidered, Orientations Toward Death: A Vital Aspect of the Study of Lives, draft of Dying and Behavior Change
  - ESS Death Articles., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Includes Orientations Toward Death, On the Deromanticization of Death
  - Death, Suicide, & Melville articles., 1960s & 1980s. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Includes draft of A Psychological Autopsy of Malcolm Melville's Death, Suicide entry in The Encyclopedia Britannica, draft of Suicide: Its Impact on Survivors, draft of Reflections on Contemporary Death, Essays in Self-Destruction
  - Medical Bulletin ESS articles., 1961 - 1963. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Assessment Articles., undated. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Schizophrenia patients in-take profile., 1940s. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - MAPS - study results chapter., 1940s. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - FFRP., 1940s. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - The Socio-Psychological Matrix of Suicide., 1960. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Suicide Among General Medical…., 1963. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Some Reflections on Death & Suicide., 1965. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Preventing Suicide., 1965 May. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Suicide Prevention Telephone Service., 1965. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - LA Suicide Prevention Center., 1965. (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Projective Techniques., 1965. (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Preventing Suicide., 1965. (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Orientations Toward Death… reply ESS., 1966. (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Orientations Toward Death., 1966. (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Orientations Toward Death., 1966 March. (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - The Logics of Communication., 1966. (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - The Logics of Communication: A Manual for Analysis by ESS., 1966. (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Suicide Prevention Around the Clock., 1966. (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Case History and Hospitalization Factors., 1966. (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - State Programs in Suicide Prevention., 1966 December 6. (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - How to Prevent Suicide., 1967. (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Sleep and Self-Destruction: A Phenomenological Approach ESS., 1967. (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Feasibility Study on Computerizing Logical Patterns by ESS., 1967. (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Suicidal Phenomena: Their Definition and Classification., 1968. (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Prologue of On the Nature of Suicide., 1969. (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - On the Nature of Suicide., 1969. (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Psycho-logic & Logical Content Analysis., 1969. (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Aspects of Depression., 1970. (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Reactions to "The Enemy"., 1970. (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Perturbation and Lethality as Precursors of in Gifted Group ESS., 1971. (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Perturbation and Lethality as Precursors., 1971. (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - You and Death., 1971. (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - On the Deromantization of Death., 1971. (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Suicide ESS., 1972. (Box 22, Folder 44)
    Encyclopedia Britannica entry
  - Some Reflections on Suicide., 1972. (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - "Nixon's Logic" & debate transcripts., 1972. (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Suicide Notes Reconsidered., 1973. (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Suicide Notes Reconsidered., 1973. (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - Postvention: The Care of the Bereaved., 1975. (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Psychologic Theory of Suicide ESS., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Suicide Article: Suicide and Success., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Suicide ESS., ca 1977. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Death and Dying ESS., ca 1977. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Aspects of the Dying Process., 1977 August. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Four Components of the Suicidal Act ESS., 1978. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - A Bibliography of Suicide Notes: 1856-1979. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Risk Writing: A Special Note about Cesare Pavese and Joseph Conrad ESS., 1979. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Risk Writing: A Special Note about Cesare Pavese and Joseph Conrad., 1979. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Pavese., 1980. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Pavese., 1980. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Psychotherapy with Suicidal Patients., 1980. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - A Possible Classification of Suicidal Acts Based on Murray's Need System ESS., ca 1980. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - The Psychological Autopsy., 1981. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Pavese., 1982. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - The Suicidal Logic of Cesare Pavese ESS., 1982. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Personality and Social Psychology ESS., 1982. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Aspects of the personaological System of Henry A. Murray ESS., 1982. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - On Abolishing Death: An Etymological Note ESS., 1983. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Can Suicide be Prevented ESS., 1983 September. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Some Essentials of Suicide., 1984. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Approaches and Commonalities of Suicide., 1985. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - MAPS of the Harvard Yard ESS., 1986. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - A Psychological Approach to Suicide., 1986. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Dying, Denying and Willing the Obligatory ESS., 1987. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Life-Span Issues with Respect to the Commonalities of Suicide by ESS paper., 1988 May 27. (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - NEJM., 1992. (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Draft of Clues to Suicide, Reconsidered., 1994. (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Suicide on my Mind., 1998. (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Suicide and Death in Japan., undated. (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Ch. 7 Pavese & outline., undated. (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Logic Analysis., undated. (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Bulletin of Suicidology., 1995. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    Includes articles by ESS
  - Bulletin of Suicidology., 1995. (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Original copy of ESS' dissertation., 1948. (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Thematic Test Analysis page proof., 1951. (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Ms. In Preparation Book Suicidology editor ESS Publisher Prentice Hall., 1965. (Box 23, Folder 36)
    Likely part of Essays in Self-Destruction
  - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Table of Contents - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Part I - Literary & Philosophic Essays - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Part II - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Part III - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Part IV - Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Dr. Murray's Chap. Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Weisman's Chap. - 4th Copy Essays in Self-Destruction., 1967. (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Approvals for Death and the College Student., 1969. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Suicide Among the Gifted (1 of 3)., 1976. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Chapter in Suicidology: Contemporary Developments
  - Suicide Among the Gifted (2 of 3)., 1976. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Suicide Among the Gifted (3 of 3)., 1976. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Suicide Among the Gifted., 1976. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Voices of Death responses., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Frontes matter [eventually Voices of Death]., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Voices of Death manuscript., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Rutters of Death., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Draft of chapter 1 in Voices of Death
  - The Rutters of Death., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - # 1 VOD., 1977 October. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - 2 VOD., 1977 October. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    Draft of chapter 2 in Voices of Death
  - 3., 1977 October. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    Draft of chapter 3 in Voices of Death
  - Suicide notes/Chapter 3., ca 1977. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 3 VOD Footnotes., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Voices of Death: A Diary of Suicide., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 3 - Suicidal Careers - VOD., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Malignancy: Dialogues with Life Threatening Illnesses ESS., undated. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    Draft of possibly chapter 5 in Voices of Death
  - Chapter 7 - Suicidal Careers - VOD., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 19)
    Draft of chapter 7 in Voices of Death
  - Chapter 7 Suicidal Careers: Diaries and Journals., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Self-Destructive Mind., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 21)
    Draft of chapter 4 in Voices of Death
  - Chapter 7 V of D., ca 1980. (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Voices of Death., 1980. (Box 24, Folder 23)
    Typewritten notes on Beatrice Kern for Voices of Death
  - Draft of Definition of Suicide., 1985. (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Definition of Suicide (Master Copy) Part 1, 2 (1 of 3)., 1985. (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Definition of Suicide Part 3, 4 (2 of 3)., 1985. (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Definition of Suicide Part 5, 6, 7 (3 of 3)., 1985. (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - The Definition of Suicide., 1985. (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Shneidman -- Publications., 1989. (Box 24, Folder 29)
    copy of A Life in Death and selected articles
  - Death and the Death Certificate & Notes., 1971. (Box 24, Folder 30)
    Drafts and notes for Chapter 4 The Death Certificate in Death: Current Perspectives
  - Death: Current Perspectives, 4th Ed., 1995. (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Book Ch 1., 1998. (Box 24, Folder 32)
    The Suicidal Mind
  - Post Suicidal Reflections., 1998. (Box 24, Folder 33)
    The Suicidal Mind - Ch. 4
  - 10cc Cube Vignettes., 1998. (Box 24, Folder 34)
    The Suicidal Mind - Ch. 7
  - Life Histories., 1998. (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Manuscript for Why We Kill Ourselves (1 of 2)., 1998. (Box 24, Folder 36)
    Draft of The Suicidal Mind
  - MS (2 of 2)., 1998. (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Lives and Deaths., 1999. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Copies of works included in this collection
  - Lives & Deaths., 1999. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Autopsy of a Suicidal Mind., 2004. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The Logic of Politics., 1963. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Chapter in Television and Human Behavior edited by Mark May & Leon Arons
  - The College Student and Death., ca 1965. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Possibly chapter in The Meaning of Death edited by Herman Feifel
  - Suicide and the Two Psychologies., 1975. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Chapter in Perlin's Handbook for the Study of Suicide
  - Death and Dying Chapter in Psychology., 1977. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Thanatologie and krankenkaus., 1983. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Conspectus., ca 1991. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Chapter in Assessment & Prediction of Suicide
  - Postvention and the Survivor-Victim., 2008. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    Chapter in A Commonsense Book of Death
  - Reviews of ESS Works., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of Others's Work., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Pioneer in Suicidology review., 1963. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - AO L.I. Dublin., 1963. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Book Reviews., 1970s. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - ESS reviews by & of., 1970s - 1990s. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Review of the Creative Artist and the Savage God., 1972. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Suicidology reviews., 1976 - 1977. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Reviews/Abstracts of ES' authored work., 1980. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Letters regarding publishing manuscripts., 1982. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - New England Journal of Medicine Book Review Lifelines., 1982 - 1983. (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - The American Journal of Psychiatry., 1959 May. (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - The American Journal of Psychology., 1964 December. (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Bulletin of Suicidology., 1967 & 1995. (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Documenta Geigy., 1959 August. (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - NIH., 1965 November 2. (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Omega., 1960s. (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Psychiatric Annuals (work papers)., 1970s. (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Public Health Reports., 1962 July. (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Quadrant., 1969 Winter. (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - WRL., 1969 May - June. (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Pamphlets Developed by Others., undated. (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - In grenzenloser Unempfindlichkeit., 1980. (Box 25, Folder 33)
    Hard copy of German print of Voices of Death
  - Alien Bottlepost No. 4., undated. (Box 25, Folder 34)
    seemingly unpublished
  - The Banality of Suicide., undated. (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - D & S., 1989 & 1990. (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Dealing With Dying., undated. (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Dealing with Dying., ca 1990. (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Death & God, Post-self, Post-Self & Immort., undated. (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Death Today., undated. (Box 25, Folder 40)
    possibly an early table of contents for Death: Current Perspectives
  - Haydon., undated. (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Drafts of History of Death Certificates., undated. (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Immolator., undated. (Box 25, Folder 43)
    possibly related to the chapter on Beatrice Bessen in The Suicidal Mind
  - Inside the Self-Destructive Mind proposal abstract., undated. (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Draft of Megadeath: Children of the Bomb., 1969. (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - Notes & Lives (Dwarf & Clara)., undated. (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Notes on yellow., undated. (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - On Aspects of Dying., undated. (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - Patterns of Dying and Psychotherapeutic Interventions., undated. (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Personal Documents of Death., undated. (Box 25, Folder 50)
    possibly related to Voices of Death or Death Notes?
  - Philosophies of Death., undated. (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - A Pragmatical View of Suicide., ca 1980. (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - Prevention, Intervention & Postvention., undated. (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - Prospectus of Whispers of Death., 1980. (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - Psycho-Logic: An Explication of Argument., undated. (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - Reflections of an Immolator., undated. (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - Return to Life., ca 1973. (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - Some Essentials of Suicide., 1984 May 24. (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - Voices of Death or The Suicidal Mind., undated. (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - Suicide, Lethality, & the Psychological Autopsy., undated. (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - Introduction., undated. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Working title: Suicide Notes and Reflections; possibly Voices of Death or Autopsy of a Suicidal Mind
  - Contracts, Outlines, Foreword, etc., undated. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Working Title: Death Notes; possibly Voices of Death or Autopsy of a Suicidal Mind
  - Statement of the Thesis., undated. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Suicide Notes as Personal Documents., undated. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Possibly related to Voices of Death or Autopsy of a Suicidal Mind
  - Suicide Notes as Personal Documents., undated. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    possibly Voices of Death or Autopsy of a Suicidal Mind
  - Towards a Classification of Death Types Chapter 2., undated. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Two Concepts Related to Death and Suicide: The "Post-Self" and "Unplugging" (Submitted to APA)., 1965. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Unplugging, draft & notes., undated. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Possibly notes for The Suicidal Mind
  - CH 5 A Variety of Definitions of Death., undated. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - WEP Suicide., undated. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - WEP (Suicide Prevention)., undated. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The Aeroplane., 1992. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    seemingly unpublished fiction
  - The Aeroplane [by ESS] drafts & correspondence., ca 1992. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - The Bottle (Pending)., undated. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - The Diary., undated. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - The Diary drafts and correspondence., 1982. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - The Garden., 1985 November. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - The Garden includes correspondence., 1986 - 1987. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - In the Light of Jane Gooddall., undated. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - A Pod of Poems., 1999. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Stasis, JFK., ca 1969. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Stolter's Death., ca 1972. (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Stolter's Death including drafts and correspondence., ca 1968 - 1970. (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Writings (mostly fiction)., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Others' Creative Writing., undated. (Box 26, Folder 25)
- Herman Melville documents, Series 4.
  - Correspondence Re: Malcolm Melville., 1971. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - David - Melville., 1970s - 1990s. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Includes photograph from Moby Dick movie, Melville correspondence
  - Deaths of Herman Melville., 1966. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Deaths of Herman Melville - ESS Ms. In preparation…., 1964 - 1966. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Deaths of H.M., 1966. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - The Deaths of Herman Melville., ca 1969. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - The Deaths of Herman Melville., 1960s. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Death of Malcolm Melville., 1960s. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Malcolm., 1975 & 1976. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Hemingway Content., 1987. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Literary Pamphlets & Catalogues., 1980s - 1990s. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - The Logic of Moby Dick., undated. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Melville., 1975 December 29. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Melville., 1980s - 1990s. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Melville as Father., 1970s - 1980s. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Melville Centenary Symposium UCLA., 1991. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Melville Chapter - text/corresp., 1983 - 1986. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Melville Charts., 1966. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Melville Course., 1985 Spring. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Melville Index Cards., undated. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Melville, Malcolm, death certificate (negative, Photostat, and photographic copies)., undated. (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Melville - Parker Driving., 1976 & 1980. (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Melville Reception Notes., 1991. (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Melville-related Items., 1950s - 1990s. (Box 27, Folder 24)
    Includes correspondence, layout of Melville exhibit at UCLA
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 27, Folder 25)
    Includes a Melville Society Extracts, The Beacon, correspondence
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 27, Folder 26)
    Includes pamphlets, catalogues, correspondence
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 1990s. (Box 27, Folder 27)
    Includes correspondence, writings, publications
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 1990s. (Box 27, Folder 28)
    Includes South Sea Whale Fishery photos, copy of The New Yorker, correspondence, articles
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 2000s. (Box 27, Folder 29)
    Includes photos of UCLA's Melville exhibit, correspondence, writings
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 2000s. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Includes slides of Gilbert Wilson's "Moby Dick" works, articles, Melville Society Extracts, correspondence
  - Melville-related Items., 1960s - 2000s. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence, pamphlets, writings
  - Melville-related Items., 1970s. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Includes writings, correspondence, bulletins
  - Melville-related Items., 1980s & 1990s. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Includes Moby Dick musical article & copy of a Melville Society Extracts
  - Melville Research., 1966 & 1983. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Melville Society & Misc., 1965 & 1967. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Melville Society Extracts., 1980 - 1982. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Melville Society Extracts., 1983 - 1986. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Melville Society Extracts., 1991 - 1993. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Melville Society Extracts., 1994 - 1997. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Melville Society Extracts., 1998 - 2001. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Melville Society Extracts., 2002 - 2005. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Melville Stanwix., 1970s & 1980s. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Stanwix Melville., 1980. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Melville - TV presentation., 1985 May. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Melville - UCLA., 1991 September. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Novel., undated. (Box 28, Folder 17)
    handwritten notes
  - PA of MM., undated. (Box 28, Folder 18)
    Psychological Autopsy of Malcolm Melville
  - PA MM., undated. (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - PA of MM., undated. (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - HM - PA MM., 1970s. (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - PA of MM., 1970s. (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Pod of Poems., 1980s & 1990s. (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Ridenour., 2000s. (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Six Melville Poems., 1990s. (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Town-Ho Mystery., 1991. (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Herman Melville Selected Tales & Poems., 1961. (Box 28, Folder 27)
    Paperback book
  - Pierre of the Ambiguities by Herman Melville., 1957. (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Commemorative Stamp Posters., 1984 August 16. (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - House Beautiful Magazine., 1927 February. (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Moby Dick poster., 1956. (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Newspapers from the 1850s. (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - American Psychological Association., 1965. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - AO Durheim., undated. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - AO IGA., 1986. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Aspects of the Personological System of Henry A. Murray., 1981. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Assize File., undated. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Reference Articles., 1974, 1983, 1985, 2006. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Basic Conceptual Problems in the Psychology of Thinking., 1960. (Box 29, Folder 7)